Tim Vlasuk

timvlasuk@gmail.com Bellingham, WA

Remote Engineer

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

Self motivated continual learner that has 3+ years working within software development teams with a focus on quality assurance. Experience applying broad view perspective with ability to write and understand code to contribute within the Product Lifecycle.

Work Experience

BeFunky Remote
Senior QA Engineer Dec 2020 – Present

- Follow features and bug fixes through software development cycle for weekly web releases.
- Cross Device test packaged app for release in AppStore and PlayStore.
- Collaborate with Product and Dev teams to define scope and ensure expectations are met and tracked.
- Review code changes to aid in building test scope by pinpointing affected areas of app.
- Observe trends and troubleshoot issues using Mixpanel, Sentry, and GA4.
- Engage with entire team to brainstorm and contribute to product vision and growth.
- Monitor existing Checkly and WebDriverIO tests; collaborate with devs to update tests when needed.

Bigtincan Remote

QA Engineer Dec 2019 – Dec 2020

- Ensured webApp passed local build and deployment to staging servers.
- Ran manual regression testing on web app, crm integration, and mail client add-ins.
- Pulled custom data reports in Django Shell and automated when possible.
- Worked closely with support and dev teams to trouble-shoot, document, and resolve bugs.
- Contributed to exploratory testing campaign comparing Cypress, NightwatchJS, and Postman/Newman.

Nielsen Brother Inc

Shop Tech

Sedro-Woolley, WA April 2014 – Dec 2017

- Maintained mechanic shop environment.
- Assisted in maintenance and repair of gas, diesel, and hydraulic equipment.
- Consolidated multiple loose roles into one.

Skills

Front End: JavaScript ES6+, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SEO/WebVitals Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Django, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, Heroku

Testing: Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Travis CI, Postman, Newman-cli

Environment Tools: Python, Git, Gitlab, Docker, Unix/Linux, OSI Model, Bash, Virtual Box **Experience Using:** GA4, Mixpanel, zenDesk, Sentry, Jira, Salesforce, Checkly, WebDriverIO

Education

THINKFUL 2018-2019

Full-Stack Web Development Program / Engineering Immersion

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.